<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Root>
  <Introduction>| The door you were led through closes behind you, leaving you alone in the room. || "Subject Ten, pick up the scepter on the table." || A clinical, monotonous voice addresses you from a loudspeaker mounted high on the wall above you. || "Walk through the archway and observe your surroundings. Do not touch anything. Do not enter any structure. Return to the archway and walk through it again." || These instructions don't entirely make sense to you, as the room is nearly empty with no other exits. || "There is a printed copy of these instructions on table. Take it with you if you need it." || Despite your efforts, the voice only repeats these directions to you and instructs you to follow them.</Introduction>
  <Zones>
    <Zone Name="the test #CHAMBER" IsDark="False">The walls and floor of this large room are solid concrete. Far above you, florescent lights hang amongst thick metal rafters. Your footsteps echo through the cavernous room. The enormous metal door through which you entered was sealed behind you. At the center of the room stands a towering monolithic archway. The monument wouldn't look out of place at Stonehenge but for the surface being completely covered in carved symbols and images. Nearby sits a small wooden table for holding items.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the #NORTH side of a farmhouse" IsDark="False">You are standing outside of an unpainted wooden farmhouse, barely more than a shack. The sky is cloudy and casts a slightly reddish twilight light over everything. In every direction as far as the eye can see the land is flat, and knee-high grass waves in a cold breeze that smells of ocean air despite no sign of the sea nearby. You don't see the archway anywhere. | The front door is on this side of farmhouse. Peeking in the windows reveals a dim, unfurnished interior.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the #EAST side of a farmhouse" IsDark="False"> You are standing outside of an unpainted wooden farmhouse, barely more than a shack. The sky is cloudy and casts a slightly reddish twilight light over everything. In every direction as far as the eye can see the land is flat, and knee-high grass waves in a cold breeze that smells of ocean air despite no sign of the sea nearby. You don't see the archway anywhere. | Far away to the east, lightning flashes rapidly in an intense thunderstorm. From this distance only a faint rumbling of thunder can be heard.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the #SOUTH side of a farmhouse" IsDark="False">You are standing outside of an unpainted wooden farmhouse, barely more than a shack. The sky is cloudy and casts a slightly reddish twilight light over everything. In every direction as far as the eye can see the land is flat, and knee-high grass waves in a cold breeze that smells of ocean air despite no sign of the sea nearby. You don't see the archway anywhere. | On the horizon to the south, a wildfire rages, billowing a column black smoke into the air.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the #WEST side of a farmhouse" IsDark="False"> You are standing outside of an unpainted wooden farmhouse, barely more than a shack. The sky is cloudy and casts a slightly reddish twilight light over everything. In every direction as far as the eye can see the land is flat, and knee-high grass waves in a cold breeze that smells of ocean air despite no sign of the sea nearby. You don't see the archway anywhere. | The peaks of mountaintops can be seen just over the horizon. They must be hundreds of miles away.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the farmhouse #INTERIOR" IsDark="False">The interior of the farmhouse is dim and dusty. An unpowered incandescent lightbulb in an undecorated fixture hangs from a rafter in the center of the room, but the connected switch mounted on the wall near the door does nothing. A stone fireplace dominates one wall of the one-room building, where the charred remains in the hearth resemble bones more than logs. Through an opening in one corner of the wooden floor, stairs lead down.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="the farmhouse #BASEMENT" IsDark="True">The basement walls match the farmhouse above but the floor is solid stone. An eight foot tall marble statue stands alone in this room, its arms outstreched toward you. It is dressed in a circus clown costume with its face painted in a malevolent glare. You don't think it was standing in that particular spot the last time you were in this room.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #TUNNEL" IsDark="False">This long, narrow concrete tunnel is lined with orange emergency lights, glowing dimly. The low ceiling forces you to duck slightly. The east end of the tunnel disappears into darkness, while the west end of the tunnel exits into a brightly lit room.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="an #ATRIUM" IsDark="False">Sunlight shines down from the clear blue sky through the glass ceiling of this expansive room. The center of the room features a bubbling fountain, and flower beds containing large ferns are scattered around the red and gold carpeted floor. Wide hallways lead to the south and west. On the north wall, a pair of aluminum swinging doors seem to lead to a kitchen.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CONCOURSE" IsDark ="False">The room is a large open area with tile floors and florescent lighting. Most of the room is filled with tables and chairs, serving as a food court between the cafeteria on the north side and the bar to the south. Scattered kiosks offer items such as cell phone cases, key chains, and surgical instruments. The entire west wall is the entrance to a movie theater. The posters are for movies familiar to you, but the actors each appear to have random extra body parts.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #FOYER" IsDark ="False">This room appears to be the main entrance to the building, except heavy metal bars are bolted and welded to the front doors. There are dents from something outside hitting the metal doors but the doors remain sealed. The front desk sits empty. A single computer sits upon it, the screen frozen on a solitaire game. Double doors with an "Employees Only" sign lead to the south. A single door leads to the west, and the north side of the room opens into an atrium.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #KITCHEN" IsDark="False">This commercial kitchen is full of large appliances and stainless steel countertops. You might think that the place was only just abandoned in the midst of preparing a meal, but all of the food in the pots and trays is completely dried out, as if it has been sitting untouched for days, perhaps weeks. Past a food serving counter to the west is a large cafeteria. In one corner, a set of stairs lead down. A set of double doors lead south, and a back hallway to the north appears to lead to a grimy exterior door.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CELLAR" IsDark="True">In stark contrast to the kitchen up the stairs, this cellar is dusty and primitive. Between the rustic wooden rafters and the stone floor, the room is full of wooden barrels and shelves lined with bottles, sacks, and dry goods. Most of the flat surfaces are painted with symbols and Latin phrases, apparently using a red liquid with a finger.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CAFETERIA" IsDark ="False">The tile floor is scattered with nothing but tables and chairs. As you walk around the room, you occasionally hear behind you a brief sound of a chair sliding on the floor, but can't ever turn around fast enough to catch any of them moving. Beyond a serving counter to the east you can see a kitchen, and the south wall is completely open to the concourse to the south.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #THEATER" IsDark ="True">Past a small foyer with a ticket booth and a concession stand with a popcorn machine, you find a single screen theater auditorium. There is no light, there seems to be no power for the lights or projector. About ten feet off the ground, dozens of marionette puppets dangle haphazardly from a ceiling too high to see in the darkness.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #BAR" IsDark ="False">A long wooden bar takes up one wall, and a billiard table sits in the center of the room, but a rancid stench hangs in the air. There are a few human corpses on the floor, decayed beyond recognition and blooming with fungus. There is a trapdoor in the floor behind the bar, and exits to the north and east.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #BATHYSPHERE" IsDark="False">Climbing down from the trapdoor in the bar and crawling through a narrow dark tunnel leads to the interior of a big metal sphere, not quite big enough to stand in. Through a circular porthole you see that you are in a bathysphere, underwater in a swimming pool. Tropical fish swim around, looking very out of place. Looking up, you can make out yourself, or someone who looks identical to you, floating on the surface of the pool, apparently dead.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="an #OFFICE" IsDark="False">This large room is full of cubicles with chest-high dividers. The office is full of people, mostly sitting at desks, but they stare motionlessly at computer screens or shuffle about mindlessly carrying papers, not reacting to your presence. On one side of the room, a doorway opens to a dark staircase going down. The door leading to the staircase appears to have been knocked off the hinges from the inside. Doors exit the office to the north, south, and west.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #GYM" IsDark="False">The concrete walls are covered in fitness posters and various types of exercise equipment stand around the room. Someone didn't put their free weights back on the rack. The office is to the east, and double doors with large windows to the north appear to lead to a swimming pool.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="an indoor #POOL" IsDark="False">A familiar chlorine scent fills the humid air. There is nothing remarkable in this room, except perhaps the large circular object deep near the bottom of the pool. The pool seems clean and well-maintained, and about 12 cubits deep. Wait, you don't know what cubits are. Why did you think of the 18-foot-deep pool in cubits?</Zone>
    <Zone Name="#UNDERWATER" IsDark="False">After diving underwater, you can see tropical fish darting around you that weren't there when you were above the surface. A large brass bathysphere is mounted on the wall of the pool near the bottom. Through a circular window in the bathysphere you see yourself, or someone who looks identical to you. They stare at you in horror, and flee through a hatch inside the bathysphere whenever you approach.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a dark and ominous #STAIRCASE" IsDark="True">Your light source seems to dim in this overbearing darkness. This narrow room has no windows or light fixtures. There is a platform between every flight of stairs at regular intervals as they zig zag down but there are no other doors to other floors. The stairs continue down into the pitch black depths.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="an #ALLEYWAY" IsDark="False">The concrete is wet from rain but the night sky is clear. The alleyway is surrounded by brick buildings on three sides, and a tall chain link fence between you and a street. You can see what appear to be multiple wolves walking around on the street, watching you but not becoming aggressive unless you approach the fence. The ground is littered with trash and in one corner there is a small greenhouse with dirty opaque windows. Doors lead into the buildings to the north, south, and east. A fire escape ladder leads up to an open window with a light on.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #GREENHOUSE" IsDark="True">The greenhouse is pitch black in the night, and probably wouldn't be much brighter in the day in the shadows of these buildings. The garden beds are bare dirt, except for one small shriveled dead plant. A plastic bottle appears to have been set up as a drip irrigation device, but it is empty.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CHAPEL" IsDark="False">Colorful sunlight streams in through stained glass windows. This seems like a typical chapel but the symbols and imagery are unfamiliar to you. There are exits to the north, east, and west, and behind the pulpit a door in the floor reveals a stone staircase down.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CRYPT" IsDark="True">The air is cold and the stone block walls are rather primitive. The rooms are filled with coffins and tombs of a wide range of ages. Behind locked iron bars, another set of stairs lead further down.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="some #CATACOMBS" IsDark="True">This maze of tunnels is roughly carved out of the solid stone. Every available nook is filled with bones, and there is water standing in some places. Are you hearing something else down here, or are your ears playing tricks on you?</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #GARAGE" IsDark="False">The concrete walls and florescent lights remind you of the test chamber. In one corner there are some luxury and classic cars of different varieties. They all look very expensive. But most of the garage is empty. Tire tracks on the painted floor indicate the movement of vehicles with treads and heavy trucks. The apparent exit seems to be collapsed. It is completely blocked by concrete rubble.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="some #BARRACKS" IsDark="False">This windowless room has evidence of a militarized prescence. There are beds and lockers for soldiers, and empty racks for weapons. Paraphernalia around the room has the same symbology as the chapel. There are some unsettling propaganda posters around the room demonizing an unnamed enemy.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #BEDROOM" IsDark="False">The room is empty and the floor has a strange texture. Looking up, the ceiling of this small room is about 30 or 40 feet away. But most remarkably, on the ceiling is a bed, dresser, desk... and a person! All upside down on the carpeted ceiling. The person seems to just be hanging out in their bedroom and doesn't seem to be able to hear you. There are wooden doors on the north, east, and west walls, and a large sliding glass door leads to a balcony to the south.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #CLOSET" IsDark="False">This small closet is full of a lot of junk.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #BATHROOM" IsDark="False">It's about what you would expect for a bathroom. Shower, tub, sink, toilet; except... it's carpeted. The entire floor is carpeted, and the walls to match. It's a thick shag carpet of a sickly yellow color. It's everywhere. In front of the shower. Up to the edges of the tub. All around the toilet. Who would do this?</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #BALCONY" IsDark="False">Sunlight shines down from the clear blue sky through the glass ceiling. The bedroom's balcony overlooks the atrium you found earlier. You see the fountain and shrubbery about thirty feet below you.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #HALL" IsDark="False">The florescent lights in this wide, windowless hallway are too bright. The boring, slightly worn, speckled, light teal vinyl tile floor runs north to south. On the north end, a pair of doors with windows lead to a white room. On the south end there is an ornately carved set of wooden doors. In the middle of the hallway, the door to the bedroom is on the west wall. It has a number plate with the digit 3, but there are no other similar doors here. On the wall across from the bedroom door, there hangs a small oil painting of a burrito on a plate.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #LIBRARY" IsDark="False">This fine room of marble floors and polished wood was filled wall to wall with shelves of books. Was. It looks like some kind of pressure wave threw all the bookcases to the edges of the room. Standing in the center of the circle of fallen shelves is the stone archway that brought you to this place.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #LABORATORY" IsDark="False">A red light on one wall blinks on and off. The counters around the room are full of strange machines, medical equipment, and chemicals. Computer monitors display molecular simulations in progress and describe viral research. In the center of the room, a clear plastic tent is set up over an empty hospital bed. At the end of one counter, some equipment has been knocked over. Someone wearing a hazmat suit without the headgear is leaned up against the wall, apparently dead. Double doors lead out to a hallway and a single door leads out the back of the laboratory to the north.</Zone>
    <Zone Name="a #WORKSHOP" IsDark="False">A bell jingled above the door as you entered the room. This place feels like a cozy little cottage in the mountains. Outside the windows it is gently snowing, and the snow has accumulated up above the bottom edges of the windows. There is a door to the outside but it is completely blocked by snow. But the room is cozy and warm because of the fire in the large stone fireplace. Most of the room is full of small workbenches, where it seems that wooden toys are being assembled and fabric dolls are being sewn. Despite all the signs that someone was just here, you don't see anyone.</Zone>
  </Zones>
  <StartingZone>CHAMBER</StartingZone>
  <Items>
    <Item Name="a typed #NOTE" StartLocation="CHAMBER" Type="X">A sheet of paper with typed text: "Instructions: (1) Pick up the scepter. (2) Walk through the archway. (3) You should find yourself within 100 meters of the archway. Observe your surroundings and find the archway. IMPORTANT: DO NOT touch or pick up anything. DO NOT enter any structure. (4) Carry the scepter through the archway again."</Item>
    <Item Name="a strange #SCEPTER" StartLocation="CHAMBER" Type="X">A strange looking scepter with a red gem.</Item>
    <Item Name="a #KEYCARD" StartLocation="OFFICE" Type="Key">A plastic card with a magnetic strip.</Item>
    <Item Name="an antique #KEY" StartLocation="UNDERWATER" Type="Key">A very old key.</Item>
    <Item Name="a length of #ROPE" StartLocation="CLOSET" Type="Key">About 50 feet of a thick synthetic rope.</Item>
    <Item Name="a shattered #VIAL" StartLocation="LABORATORY" Type="X">A broken glass vial, only held together by the label.</Item>
    <Item Name="a #FLASHLIGHT" StartLocation="LABORATORY" Type="Light" ActivateMessage="You turn on the flashlight." DeactivateMessage="You turn off the flashlight.">A small waterproof flashlight.|A small waterproof flashlight, shining brightly.</Item>
  </Items>
  <ZoneConnections>
    <Connection Start="CHAMBER" Direction="In" End="SOUTH" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="NORTH" Direction="East" End="EAST" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="NORTH" Direction="West" End="WEST" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="EAST" Direction="North" End="NORTH" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="EAST" Direction="South" End="SOUTH" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="SOUTH" Direction="East" End="EAST" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="SOUTH" Direction="West" End="WEST" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="WEST" Direction="North" End="NORTH" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="WEST" Direction="South" End="SOUTH" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="NORTH" Direction="In" End="INTERIOR" />
    <Connection Start="INTERIOR" Direction="Down" End="BASEMENT" />
    <Connection Start="BASEMENT" Direction="West" End="TUNNEL" />
    <Connection Start="TUNNEL" Direction="West" End="ATRIUM" />
    <Connection Start="ATRIUM" Direction="West" End="CONCOURSE" />
    <Connection Start="ATRIUM" Direction="North" End="KITCHEN" />
    <Connection Start="ATRIUM" Direction="South" End="FOYER" />
    <Connection Start="KITCHEN" Direction="West" End="CAFETERIA" />
    <Connection Start="KITCHEN" Direction="North" End="ALLEYWAY" />
    <Connection Start="KITCHEN" Direction="Down" End="CELLAR" />
    <Connection Start="ALLEYWAY" Direction="North" End="OFFICE" />
    <Connection Start="ALLEYWAY" Direction="Up" End="BEDROOM" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="ALLEYWAY" Direction="In" End="GREENHOUSE" />
    <Connection Start="ALLEYWAY" Direction="East" End="CHAPEL" />
    <Connection Start="OFFICE" Direction="North" End="FOYER" />
    <Connection Start="OFFICE" Direction="West" End="GYM" />
    <Connection Start="OFFICE" Direction="Down" End="STAIRCASE" />
    <Connection Start="STAIRCASE" Direction="Down" End="STAIRCASE" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="GYM" Direction="North" End="POOL" />
    <Connection Start="POOL" Direction="Down" End="UNDERWATER" />
    <Connection Start="FOYER" Direction="West" End="BAR" />
    <Connection Start="CONCOURSE" Direction="North" End="CAFETERIA" />
    <Connection Start="CONCOURSE" Direction="West" End="THEATER" />
    <Connection Start="CONCOURSE" Direction="South" End="BAR" />
    <Connection Start="BAR" Direction="Down" End="BATHYSPHERE" />
    <Connection Start="CHAPEL" Direction="North" End="GARAGE" />
    <Connection Start="CHAPEL" Direction="East" End="BARRACKS" />
    <Connection Start="CHAPEL" Direction="Down" End="CRYPT" />
    <Connection Start="CRYPT" Direction="Down" End="CATACOMBS" Key="KEY" />
    <Connection Start="WORKSHOP" Direction="South" End="LABORATORY" />
    <Connection Start="LABORATORY" Direction="South" End="HALL" Key="KEYCARD" />
    <Connection Start="HALL" Direction="South" End="LIBRARY" />
    <Connection Start="HALL" Direction="West" End="BEDROOM" />
    <Connection Start="BEDROOM" Direction="West" End="BATHROOM" />
    <Connection Start="BEDROOM" Direction="In" End="CLOSET" />
    <Connection Start="BEDROOM" Direction="South" End="BALCONY" />
    <Connection Start="BALCONY" Direction="Down" End="ATRIUM" Key="ROPE" OneWay="True" />
    <Connection Start="LIBRARY" Direction="In" End="CHAMBER" OneWay="True" />
  </ZoneConnections>
</Root>
